in this video I want to help you gain an
在这个视频中我想帮助你获得
intuitive understanding of calculus and
对微积分和导数直观的理解
the derivatives now maybe you're
或许你认为
thinking that you haven't seen calculus
你再也没有接触微积分
since your college days and depending on
自从大学后，这取决于你
when you graduate maybe that was quite
什么时候毕业，也许有
some time back now if that's what you're
一段时间了，如果你顾虑这点
thinking don't worry you don't need a
请不要担心，你并不需要
deep understanding of calculus in order
非常深入理解微积分，为了
to apply neural networks and deep learning
高效应用神经网络和深度学习
very effectively so if you're watching
因此如果你观看
this video or some of the later videos
这个视频或者以后的视频
be wondering wow this stuff really for
时心想：哇喔，这些知识
me this calculus looks really
这些运算对我来说真的
complicated my advice to you is the
很复杂，我给你的建议是
following which is that watch the videos
坚持学习视频
and then if you could do the homework
最好做下课后作业
and complete the programming homework
成功地完成编程作业
successfully then you can apply deep
然后你就可以使用深度
learning in fact what you see later is
学习了，事实上之后你将看到
that in week 4 will define a couple of
在第4周将会定义
types of functions that will enable you
很多种类的函数类型，它们能够帮助你把
to encapsulate everything that needs to
所有需要的知识结合起来
be done with respect to calculus that
通过微积分
these functions called forward functions
其中有叫做前向函数
and backward functions that you learn
和反向函数的函数，因此你
about that let you put everything you
不需要了解所有你使用的
need to know about calculus into these
那些微积分中的函数
functions so that you don't need to
因此你无需
worry about them anymore beyond that but
担心它们，除此之外
I thought that in this foray into deep
在对深度学习的尝试中
learning that this week we should open
这周我们
up the box and peer a little bit further
要一探究竟，进一步深入
into the details of calculus but really
了解微积分的细节
all you need is an intuitive
所有你确实需要的东西只是
understanding of this in order to build
直观地认识微积分，用来构建
and successfully apply these algorithms
和成功的应用这些算法
oh and finally if you are among that
最后，如果你是
maybe smaller group of people that are
小部分人群，那些
expert in calculus if you're very
精通微积分的一员，你对
familiar with calculus observe this it's
微积分非常熟悉
probably okay for you to skip this video
你可以跳过这部分视频
but for everyone else let's dive in and
其他同学，让我们开始
try to get an intuitive understanding of
深入学习
derivatives I've plotted here the
导数。我在这里画了一个
function f of a equals 3a so it's just
函数，f(a)=3a,它是
a straight line to gain intuition about
一条直线，来简单理解
derivatives let's look at a few points
导数。让我们看看
on this function let's say that a is
函数中几个点，假定a
equal to 2 in that case f of a which is
等于2,那么f(a)
equal to 3 times a is equal to 6 so if a
等于a的3倍,等于6，也就是说如果a
is equal to 2 then you know F of a will
等于2,那么函数f(a)
be equal to 6 let's say we give the
等于6.假定我们
value of a you know just a little bit of
稍微改变a的值，只变一点点
a nudge I'm going to just bump up me a
移动，只增加
little bit so there is now 2.00 1 right
一点点，2.001
so I'm going to get a like a tiny little
我将微小的
nudge to the right so now is let's say 2.001
右移，这时是2.001
this plug this is to scale 2.001
这个坐标值是2.001
the 0.001 difference is too small to
0.001的差别实在太小了
show on this plot this give them a
不能在图中显示，我们
little nudge to the right now f of a is
把它右移一点，现在f(a)
equal to three times a so six point
等于a的3倍是
zero zero three,Simplot this over here
6.003,画在这里
this is not to the scale this is six point
比例不太符合，这是
zero zero three so if you look at this
6.003，你看
low triangle here some highlighting in
这个小三角形，绿色高亮部分
green what we see is that if I match a
如果我
0.001 to the right then F of a goes up
向右移动0.001，那么f(a)增加
by 0.003 the amount that F of a went up
0.003，f的值增加
is three times as big as the amount that
3倍于
I judged nudging a to the right so we're going
右移的a,因此我们
to say that the slope of the derivative
说：斜率，这个导数
of the function f of a at a equals two
函数f(a)在a等于2
or when a is equal to 2 the slope is
或者说，当a=2时，斜率是
three and you know the term derivative
3，导数这个概念
basically means slope is just that
基本意味着斜率
derivative sound like a scary a more
导数听起来是一个很可怕
intimidating word whereas slope is a
很令人惊恐的词，但是斜率以一种
friendlier way to describe the concept
很友好的方式来描述导数这个
of derivative so one of these year
概念，所以有时提到
derivative just think slope of the
导数，把它当做函数的斜率
function and more formally the slope is
就好了，更正式的斜率
defined as the height divided by the
定义为高除以
width of this little triangle that we
宽，在这个绿色小三角形
have in green so this is you know 0.003
即0.003
over 0.001 and the fact that the slope is
除以0.001，斜率
equal to 3 or the derivative is equal 3
等于3，或者说导数等于3
just represents the fact that when you
这表示当你
nudge a to the right by 0.001 by tiny
将a右移0.001，移动一点点
amount the amount that F of a goes up is
f(a)的数额增加
three times as big as the amount that
3倍的量
united the united a in the horizontal
水平方向a的总量
direction so that's all that the slope
这就是这条线的斜率
of a line is now let's look at this
现在让我们看看
function at a different point let's say
这个函数，从不同的角度
that a is now equal to five
假设a等于5
in that case f of a three times a is
此时f(a),3乘以a
equal to 15 so let's say I again give a
等于15，我再一次
and notch to the right
右移a
a tiny level less is now bumped up to
很小幅度，增加到
five point oo one F of a is three
5.001,f(a)等于
times that
3倍
so f of a is equal to fifteen point zero
f(a)等于15.003
three and so once again when I bump up a to
再一次当我增加a
the right nudge a to the right by 0.001
将a右移0.001
F of a goes up three times as much
f(a)增加3倍
so the slope again at a equals five is
所以在a等于5时，斜率
also three so the way we write is that
是3，所以我们将
the slope of the function f is equal to
函数f等于3的斜率表达为
three we say D F of a da and this just
d f(a)/da
means the slope of the function f of a
这表示f(a)的斜率
when you nudge the variable a a tiny
当你微小改变变量a
little amount um this is equal to three
的值，它等于3
and an alternative way to write this
一个替代方式表达
derivative formula is as follows you can
导数公式是你可以
also write this as d da of f of a so
这样写，d/da f(a)
whether you put the f of a on top of
不管你是否将f(a)放在上面
whether you write it you know down here
或是放在这里（右边）
it doesn't matter
都没有关系
but all those equation means is that if
这些等式表示如果
I nudge a to the right a little bit
将a右移一点
I expect F of a to go up by three times
那么f(a)增加3倍
as much as I nudge just the value of
我移动a的值
little a now for this video I explained
在这个视频中我讲解
derivatives talking about what happens
导数，谈论的情况是
we nudge the variable a by 0.001 um if
我们将变量a偏移0.001，如果
you want the formal mathematical
你想知道正式的
definition of the derivatives
导数数学定义
derivatives are defined with an even
导数是
smaller value of how much you nudge a to
你右移a非常小的值
the right so it's not often 00 1 is not
不是0.001
0.00000001 is not 0.0ooooo and so on 1 is sort of
不是0.00000001，不是0.00000..1,是
even smaller than that and the formal
非常非常小的值,通常
definition of derivative says what have
导数的定义是
you nudge a to the right by an info
你右移a以
testable amount basically an infinite
可度量的值
infinitely tiny tiny amount if you do
一个无限小的值
that just f of a go up three times as
f(a)增加3倍
much as whatever was a tiny tiny tiny
增加了一个非常非常小的值
amount that you now stay to the right so
也就是在这个三角形右边的变化值
that's actually the formal definition of
那就是导数的正式定义
a derivative but for the purposes of our
但是为了
intuitive understanding we're going to
直观的认识，我们将
talk about nudging a to the right by
探讨右移a以
this small amount 0.001 even if it's
0.001这个值即使
0.001 isn't exactly you know tiny tiny
0.001并不是无穷小的
insa testable now one property of the
可测数据.导数的一个特性是
derivative is that no matter where you
这个函数任何
take the slope of this function it is
地方的斜率总是
equal to 3 whether a is equal to 2 or a
等于3不管a等于2或a
is equal to 5 the slope of this function
等于5，这个函数的斜率
is equal to 3 meaning that whatever is
总等于3，也就是说不管
the value of a if you increase it by
a的值如何，如果你增加
0.001 that
0.001
value of f of a goes up by three times
f(a)的值就增加3倍
as much so this function has the same
这个函数在所有地方的
slope everywhere and one way to see that
斜率都相等.一种证明的方式是
is that wherever you draw this your
无论你将小三角形
little triangle right the height divided
画在哪里，它的高除以
by the width always has a ratio of three
宽的比值总是3
to one so I hope this gives you a sense
比1.我希望带给你一种感受
of what the slope what the derivative of
什么是斜率什么是导函数
the function means for a straight line
对于一条直线
where in this example the slope of the
在例子中函数的斜率
function was three everywhere in the
在任何地方都是3
next video let's take a look at a
在下一个视频中让我们看看
slightly more complex example where the
一个更复杂的例子
slopes of the function can be different
我们将提到的这个函数的斜率是可变的
at different points on the function
当在函数图像上不同的点时